Contact

9888981003 (Mobile) soul.tarun@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ tarungupta003 (LinkedIn) tarungupta.brandyourself.com/ (Other) blogs.tarungupta.info (Blog) tarungupta.info (Personal)

Top Skills

JavaScript

PHP

Node.js

Languages

English

Hindi

Punjabi

Certifications

M101JS: MongoDB for Node.js Developers Learn HTML5

Honors-Awards

Scholarship for Post Graduation 2nd Prize in Fight-Eng Inter University Competition

Publications

Information Governance

Tarun Gupta

Full Stack Software Engineer, System Architect, Open Source Expert, Technology Consultant and Advisor

Jalandhar, Punjab, India

Summary

Tarun is currently working at VenturePact as a part of the software development team and serving as a Team/Tech Lead. Tarun possesses 6+ years of experience in web, mobile and software development. With a Bachelor's and a Master Degree in Information Technology, Tarun possesses deep academic knowledge as well as extensive practical experience. He likes to make cool and functional web apps. His works are always safe and compatible with latest trends & Technology.

Tarun, primarily skilled in the following technologies:

PHP(Almost all CMS's and Frameworks)
MySql
Node.js
Angualr.js
MongoDb

Tarun enjoy travelling, tracking, football, chess and most love coding:)

Experience

VenturePact Team Lead June 2017 - Present

Outgrow is a growth marketing platform that enables marketers to build interactive content/tools to increase customer engagement and boost demand generation with no custom design or development.

Marketers can build tools ranging from highly converting interactive calculators that calculate costs, savings, RoI, risk to quizzes and recommendation tools that are highly viral and bring in new referral traffic.

Think: What is a fair auto-insurance premium? What is the Rol on Marketing Automation? Which sunglasses best fit my style? Do I need a Database Administrator? What is the cost of remodelling my kitchen? What is your risk of catching Zika?

My responsibilities includes

- Site wide Development in Frontend(angular2) + Backend(mongodb and Nodeis)
- Managing Outgrow servers(Linux) with different environments(Dev Staging Production) for deployment
- Defining process of development and execution
- Handling dev team for development
- Integration of the product to marketing CRM like Hubspot, Marketo, Salesforce, Pardot etc.
- Customized billing management using 3rd party Chargebee, Stripe
- Handling marketing development of the product like blog, google analytics, SEO, intercom etc

Lovely Professional University Project Officer June 2012 - Present

Working as Software Developer at Division of InfoTech (Software Development) for the development and management of an award winning ERP solution known as "University Management System" for Lovely Professional University.

The System has been designed to process all the academic and administrative tasks of the University. The System is used by more than 30000+ students and 3500+ staff members, as the University aspires to become one of the Paperless Universities on the Globe.

Our University Management System has been awarded "Best IT Innovation in Higher Education" at INDIA 3.0 IT Innovation Awards powered by NASSCOM and CNBC TV18.

Skill-set: C#.NET ,VB.NET, ASP.NET, MS SQL Server, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, XML, Crystal Report, Microsoft Office, Photoshop,PHP , CakePHP , Drupal,Joomla,Wordpress,Python

Also working as an entrepreneurship trainer for PHP and .Net

Outgrow.co
Team Leader
May 2016 - Present

Outgrow is a growth marketing platform that enables marketers to build interactive content/tools to increase customer engagement and boost demand generation with no custom design or development.

Marketers can build tools ranging from highly converting interactive calculators that calculate costs, savings, RoI, risk to quizzes and recommendation tools that are highly viral and bring in new referral traffic.

Think: What is a fair auto-insurance premium? What is the Rol on Marketing Automation? Which sunglasses best fit my style? Do I need a Database Administrator? What is the cost of remodelling my kitchen? What is your risk of catching Zika?

My responsibilities includes

- Site wide Development in Frontend(angular2) + Backend(mongodb and Nodejs)
- Managing Outgrow servers(Linux) with different environments(Dev Staging Production) for deployment
- Defining process of development and execution
- Handling dev team for development
- Integration of the product to marketing CRM like Hubspot, Marketo, Salesforce, Pardot etc.
- Customized billing management using 3rd party Chargebee, Stripe
- Handling marketing development of the product like blog, google analytics, SEO, intercom etc

VenturePact

4 years 8 months

Senior Software Engineer August 2013 - June 2017 (3 years 11 months) Jalandhar Area. India Its a great experience working on AWS services. I have resolved all our company domains(DNS) into Windows server2008, Managing all clients' websites on WIndows and Linux environment.

Software Engineer November 2012 - August 2013 (10 months) Jalandhar Area, India

VenturePact is an invite only marketplace that connects companies with trusted software development firms.

Finding a vetted development company that matches your requirements and preferences is challenging as there are many software service providers around the world with varying levels of quality and specialty. This makes it hard for experienced development shops to stand out especially given that clients are usually located in different countries. Our marketplace addresses these issues by connecting companies with the best software service providers that fit their needs.

Our service providers are skilled in open source, mobile and web technologies including iphone (iOS), Android, Windows, Python, Ruby, Node.js, Php, .NET, scala, Java, javascript, CSS, HTML, sharepoint, wordpress, drupal, joomla, MYSQL, mongoDB, cyber security, salesforce integration, user interface and user experience (UI/UX) or web design and many more.

With the new era of companies focusing on doing a few things well, instead of trying to build everything in house, we want to streamline the entire process of finding, screening, onboarding, negotiating and paying service providers around the world.

At VenturePact, I work on developing the marketplace platform.

I'm responsible for developing web application in different programming languages(PHP,.NET,Node.js etc), Managing groups of developers, Clients management, AWS management for DNS and website hosting

smartData Enterprises Software Associate January 2012 - June 2012 (6 months)

Worked as a Software associate and was responsible for the client interaction and development of the application using PHP and CakePHP.

Worked on Drupal and WordPress for some Applications.

Education

Lovely Professional University

Master's Degree, Computer Application · (2009 - 2012)

CT Institute of Management and IT

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Application · (2006 - 2009)